Guide to the New-York Historical Society Postcard Collection [graphic] circa 1898-1965 (bulk, 1900-1950) PR 54
New-York Historical Society
New-York Historical Society postcard collection [graphic]
circa 1898-1965
New-York Historical Society
PR 54
approximately 57 Linear feet (in 105 boxes)
The New-York Historical Society Postcard Collection contains approximately 62,000 postcard views of the United States, New York State, New York City and international geographic locations, depicting, buildings, historical scenes, modes of transportation, tourist attractions, holiday greetings and other subjects. The collection is strongest for New York City.
Arrangement
The New-York Historical Society Postcard Collection is divided into four series:
Series I. Geographic Locations | United States (except New York), dates from ca. 1898 to about 1965 and contains about 22,000 cards that generally depict popular tourist destinations, vacation resorts by the sea and in the mountains, prominent buildings, businesses, civic institutions, modes of transportation, and street scenes. Well-represented tourist attractions include the Grand Canyon, and the mountains of New Hampshire. Typical city souvenir cards show attractive urban life in views of public courthouses, libraries, spacious parks, expositions, and architecturally impressive office buildings and bridges. Prominent residences, historical sites, and scenes of nature are also abundant. General sections can be found at the end of most states, larger cities, and some other subsections. These include cards that show unidentified or only generally identified views.
==============================
Series II. Geographic Locations | New York, is divided into two subseries:
Subseries II.A. New York State includes cards from popular tourist attractions like Niagara Falls. A General section at the end of New York State includes views along highways, rivers, and train lines that are not geographically specified. The collection documents the changing landscape and architectural history for the areas represented. It may also be valuable source for social historians interested in researching the history of tourism, transportation and cultural identity. Some of the postcards were included as a result of the New-York Historical Society's effort to collect cards with representations of less common views of New York State, such as real photo postcards that document towns or events too small to appear in formal publications. Postcards commissioned by restaurants, hotels and other businesses also provide valuable visual documentation of sites not otherwise represented in the collection.
Subseries II.B. New York City, fills boxes 40 through 60. Cards pertaining to the city as a whole come first: general "Greetings from" cards, Bridges, Celebrations (includes the 1939 and 1964-65 World's Fairs), Future, History, Humor, Islands, and a sizable number of souvenir foldout mailers. Cards pertaining to the five boroughs come next, with the lion's share belonging to Manhattan (boxes 42-56), followed by Brooklyn, The Bronx, Queens, and Staten Island. See the container list for detailed subjects included, which are typically arranged in alphabetical order. Generally, the cards depict churches, prominent named buildings, monuments, parks, squares, and circles, banks, department stores, hotels, museums, restaurants, schools and colleges.
==============================
Series III. Geographic Locations | International, contains approximately 2,000 cards relating to Europe, the Caribbean, Canada, and other North, Central, and South American countries. Cards are arranged alphabetically by region, country, and thereunder by city, town or geographical feature. The cards focus primarily on tourist destinations such as historical sites, beaches, lakes and parks.
==============================
Series IV. Subjects, contains cards dating from ca. 1898 to 1965 which are arranged alphabetically by topic: Activities & Occupations, Advertising, American Art, American History (events, sites and memorials of historical significance in the United States), Comic, Holidays, Portraits (includes African Americans, Native Americans, and Human Curiosities), Sentimental, Transportation (largely ships and trains), and Unusual Postcards (includes cards on leather, cards on birch bark, a card on a cross section of a tree, embroidered cards and cards on fabric, cat cards, cards with feathers, cards that are drink coasters, embossed cards of New York City and State scenes, accordion-folder cards that pull open, and a lenticular print card, which, when tilted, displays alternate images of Theodore Roosevelt and the White House).
Historical Note
Postal mailing cards were introduced in the United States in the 1870s, chiefly for advertisements and business notices. Pictorial souvenir cards issued in 1893 for the World's Columbian Exposition popularized view cards. The 1898 reduction in postcard postage, from two cents to a penny, triggered a flood of card production. Millions of cards were mailed and collected annually in the United States through World War I. As postcards became more popular, publishers began addressing new subjects, with holidays, patriotic sentiments, political campaigns, and social issues gaining popularity in the first decade of the twentieth century.
The Albertype Company, begun in 1889 in Brooklyn, New York, produced photographic views, postcards, and souvenir booklets for areas across the United States. The company's output eventually reached several million pictures per year. The Albertype Company ceased operation shortly after the death of Herman L. Wittemann, the son of one of the founding Wittemann brothers, in 1952.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The New-York Historical Society Postcard Collection contains cards from a variety of sources. Among the larger contributions are 3,340 cards donated by Samuel V. Hoffman in 1941. Hoffman, a postcard collector, began systematically searching for postcards with views of New York City in the 1890s and continued to collect them through the 1940s. And approximately 10,000 postcards in the collection came from the stock file of the Brooklyn-based Albertype Company in 1953.
Smaller donations of random postcards have come in over time. These were not carefully documented in the past, but simply slipped into the appropriate categories of the collection. Contributions since 2017 have come from
• Adrienne Alexander (PPAC.2017.056)
• Anonymous (PPAC.2022.008)
• Patricia Appelt (PPAC.2021.031)
• Susan Baker (PPAC.2019.040)
• Balaton Area Historical Society, Balaton, MN (PPAC.2022.007))
• Cassie Barrow (PPAC.2019.042)
• Delores Beard (PPAC.2021.013)
• Edna Beeman (PPAC.2021.044)
• James Boone (PPAC.2018.036)
• Dianne Brackett (PPAC.2019.005)
• Christine Brandon (PPAC.2022.030)
• Ron Brown (PPAC.2022.005)
• Sarah Brown (PPAC.2018.023)
• Buffalo History Museum (PPAC.2019.060)
• Sally Chetwynd (PPAC.2021.043)
• Coventry Town Museum, Sidney, NY (PPAC.2022.006.01)
• Eagle Valley Library District, Eagle, Colorado (PPAC.2019.027)
• Nancy Eiler (PPAC.2018.019)
• JoAnne Fassinger (PPAC.2019.033)
• Karen Frome (PPAC.2021.028)
• Joshua Hamerman (PPAC.2019.002; PPAC.2019.085; PPAC.2020.004)
• Char Harris (PPAC.2019.083)
• Historic Fredericksburg Foundation, Inc. (PPAC.2019.004)
• Amber and Joseph Johnson III (PPAC.2022.009)
• Debra Johnson (PPAC.2021.012)
• Kate Kelley (PPAC.2022.042)
• Kevin Lawrence (PPAC.2017.057)
• Richard Lewis (PPAC.2022.040)
• James Litzler (PPAC.2018.052)
• Paul McKenna (PPAC.2018.060)
• Magnolia (Ohio) Area Historical Society (PPAC.2021.052)
• Sally Maish (PPAC.2021.027)
• Milford (Connecticut) Historical Society (PPAC.2021.025)
• Alicia Moran (PPAC.2021.030)
• Mountain Home Historical Society (accession no. PPAC.2017.039)
• Andrea W. Nevins-Fernandez (PPAC.2017.079)
• Ohio History Connection (PPAC.2019.018)
• Ouachita Baptist University (PPAC.2019.061)
• Stanley Pawlowski (PPAC.2021.023)
• Graham Pohl (PPAC.2022.012)
• Lori A. Pries (PPAC.2019.041)
• Rehoboth Beach Historical Society & Museum (PPAC.2017.043)
• Alvin Schaut (PPAC.2017.61; PPAC.2018.010; PPAC.2018.044; PPAC.2018.056; PPAC.2018.085; PPAC.2019.028; PPAC.2020.005; PPAC.2021.061; PPAC.2022.001)
• Sherry Scott (PPAC.2021.015)
• Edward Steele (PPAC.2018.043)
• Nadia Steinzor (PPAC.2019.032)
• Robin Tavano (PPAC.2021.029)
• Jere and Bill Voigt (PPAC.2022.041)
• Judith Zabar (PPAC.2021.076)
Related Materials
The Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collection holds other, smaller, focused collections of postcards, such as the Dale E. Jenkins collection of Manhattan restaurant postcards (PR-337), and the James Olinkiewicz collection of Brooklyn Daily Eagle postcards (PR-355). Many additional Manhattan hotel postcards may be found in the George B. Corsa Collection of hotel ephemera; click here for a list of hotels included. Related views can be found in the Stereograph File (PR-065), and additional souvenir folders (such as those in boxes (96-A through 96-D) can be found in the N-YHS Collection of Geographic Images (PR-020).
Scope and Contents
The New-York Historical Society Postcard Collection is an artificial collection, built up over time. It contains approximately 62,000 postcards which depict geographic views, buildings, historical scenes, modes of transportation, holiday greetings, and other subjects from about 1898 through roughly 1965. A variety of printing processes and postcard types are represented in the collection, including photographic, lithographic, photomechanically printed, and novelty cards, included scattered examples of hold-to-light cards, which typically depict buildings with windows that shine when the card is held to a light source.
The majority of the postcards are in excellent condition; approximately half were never mailed. Those that were mailed usually communicate simple messages that share experiences and connect the senders to family and friends.
About 10,000 cards come from the stock file of the Brooklyn-based Albertype Company. Other major publishers represented in the collection include the American Souvenir Card Company, the Illustrated Postal Card Company, and the Detroit Publishing Company.
Accruals
The New-York Historical Society continues to receive gifts of small numbers of postcards, which will be added to the collection.
Aerial views; Bird's-eye views.; Bridges -- New York (State) -- New York.; Buildings -- New York (State) -- New York.; Church buildings -- New York (State) -- New York.; Dwellings -- New York (State) -- New York; Holidays; Hotels -- New York (State) -- New York.; Monuments -- New York (State) -- New York.; Neighborhoods -- New York (State) -- New York.; New York (N.Y.) -- Description and travel.; New York (N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Parks -- New York (State) -- New York.; Photographic postcards; Picture postcards.; Postcards.; Resorts; Restaurants -- New York (State) -- New York.; Rivers -- New York (State) -- New York.; Schools -- New York (State) -- New York.; Streets -- New York (State) -- New York.; Transportation -- New York (State) -- New York.
- Series I. Geographic Locations | United States (except New York), circa 1898-1965 (bulk, 1900-1950); 21.39 Linear feet (in 39.5 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Cards are filed alphabetically by U.S. state and thereunder by city or geographical feature. Extensively represented cities are subdivided by building types, streets and other subjects.
  - Alabama (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Mobile
    Montgomery
    General
  - Alabama | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Bellingrath Gardens, Mobile
  - Alaska (Box 1)
  - Alaska | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Alaska
  - Arizona (Box 1)
    A-G
    Grand Canyon
    H-O
    Phoenix
    Prescott
    P-S
    T-Z
  - Arizona | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Grand Canyon National Park & Arizona
  - Arkansas (Box 1)
  - California (Box 1)
    A-C
    Berkeley
    Catalina Island
    Coloma
  - California (continued) (Box 2)
    D-L
    Hollywood
    Lake Tahoe
    Long Beach
    Los Angeles
    M
    Missions
    Monterey
    Mt. Lassen
    Mt. Lowe
    Mt. Shasta
    Mt. Tamalpais
    Mt. Watkins
    Mt. Wilson
    N-P
    Palo Alto
    Pasadena
    Pebble Beach
    Q-R
    Riverside
  - California (continued) (Box 3)
    S
    San Diego
    Panama-California Exposition, 1915
    San Francisco
    Panama-Pacific International Exposition, 1915
    Golden Gate International Exposition, 1939
    Santa Barbara
    Santa Cruz
    Santa Monica
    Yosemite National Park
  - California (continued) (Box 4)
  - California | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    California Missions
    California Redwoods
    California the Golden State
    Disneyland
    Homes of Movie and Television Stars
    Homes of Movie Stars
    Land of Oranges
    Mount Lowe
    Muir Woods and California Redwoods
    Fascinating San Francisco
    The Queen City
    World's Greatest Bridges
    20 Post Cards
    San Joaquin Pioneer Museum & Haggin Art Galleries
    Southern California
    Scenic Gems
    Souvenir Folding Postcard
  - California | Oversize (Box 97 (folder 1))
  - California | Miniature (Box 98)
    Oakland and Berkeley
    Points of Interest on Gray Line Tours
  - Colorado (Box 4)
    A-D
    Canyons
    Cave of the Winds
    Colorado Springs
    Denver
    E-L
    Garden of the Gods
    Lookout Mountain
    M-S
    Manitou
    Parks
    Pikes Peak
    Royal Gorge
    Telluride
    Miscellaneous
  - Colorado | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Buffalo Bill Museum & Lookout Mountain
    Colorado Midland
    Colorado Museum of Natural History
    In the Clouds
    Moffat Road
    Pike's Peak
    unidentified
  - Colorado | Oversize (Box 97 (folder 1))
  - Connecticut (Box 5)
    A-B
    Bridgeport
    C-D
    Danbury
    E-G
    Greenwich
    Groton
    Guilford
    H-L
    Hartford
    Lakeville
    Litchfield
    M-N
    Milford
    Mystic
    New Canaan
    New Haven
    New London
  - Connecticut (continued) (Box 6)
    New Preston
    Norwalk
    Norwich
    O-R
    S-V
    Stamford
    Twin Lakes
    W
    Waterbury
    Winsted
  - Connecticut | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Derby
    Wesleyan University
  - Delaware (Box 6)
    A-M
    N-R
    New Castle
    W-Z
    Wilmington
    Winterthur
  - Delaware | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Till Delaware Minnet [Swedish for "In Remembrance of Delaware"]
  - District of Columbia (Box 6)
    A-E
    American Red Cross
    Arlington Cemetery
    Bridges
    Capitol
    Churches
    Corcoran Art Gallery
    F-L
    Historic Houses
  - District of Columbia (continued) (Box 7)
    Hotels
    Library of Congress
    Lincoln Memorial
    M-O
    National Gallery of Art
    P-Z
    Rock Creek Park
    Smithsonian Institution
    Soldiers Home
    State, War & Navy Building
    Thomas Circle
    United States Post Office
    United States Supreme Court
    United States Treasury
    Union Station
    Views
    Washington Monument
    White House
  - District of Columbia | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Beautiful Washington, D.C., the Nation's Capital
    Folger Shakespeare Library
    Greetings from Washington (2)
    Pan-American Union
  - District of Columbia | Oversize (Box 97 (folder 1))
  - Florida (Box 7)
    Boca Grande
    Bradenton (Bradentown)
    Clearwater
    Daytona Beach
  - Florida (continued) (Box 8)
    Jacksonville
    M-P
    Miami
    Orlando
    Palm Beach
    R-S
    St. Augustine
    St. Petersburg
    Residences
    Street Scenes
    Tampa
  - Florida (continued) (Box 9)
    Subjects
    Animals
    Flora
    Lakes, Rivers, etc.
    Seminoles
    Tropical Scenes
  - Florida | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Beautiful Florida
    Marine Studios Marineland
    Miami Beach
    St. Augustine (2)
    Silver Springs
    Singing Tower
    Tarpon Springs
  - Florida | Oversize (Box 97 (folder 1))
  - Georgia (Box 9)
    Atlanta
    Augusta
    M-R
    S-Z
    Savannah
  - Hawaii (Box 9)
    Honolulu
  - Hawaii | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    "Aloha" Hawaiian Islands
  - Hawaii | Oversize (Box 97 (folder 1))
    Hilo City
  - Idaho (Box 9)
    N-Z
  - Illinois (Box 9-10)
    Chicago
    Art Institute
    Beaches
    Buildings
    "Century of Progress" World's Fair, 1933-1934
    Chicago Harbor
    Chicago Historical Society
    Field Museum
    Garfield Park
    Grant Park
    Humbolt Park
    Jackson Park
    Lake Shore Drive
    Lincoln Park
    Michigan Avenue and Boulevard
    Monuments
    Municipal Pier
    Restaurants
    State Street
    University of Chicago
    Washington Park
    World's Columbian Exposition, 1893
  - Illinois | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Chicago at Night
    Chicago "Queen of the Lakes"
  - Illinois | Oversize (Box 97 (folder 1))
  - Indiana (Box 10)
    A-I
    Indianapolis
    J-M
    Madison
    Q-S
    South Bend
    Terre Haute
  - Iowa (Box 11)
    Des Moines
  - Iowa | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Grotto of the Redemption, West Bend, Iowa
  - Kansas (Box 11)
  - Kentucky (Box 11)
    A-F
    Frankfort
    G-L
    Lexington
    Louisville
    M-Z
    Mammoth Cave
  - Louisiana (Box 11)
    A-N
    New Orleans
    O-Z
  - Louisiana | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Quaint Old New Orleans
    Souvenir of New Orleans, La., "The Crescent City"
  - Louisiana | Oversize (Box 97 (folder 1))
  - Maine (Box 11)
    Bangor
    Bar Harbor
    Bethel
  - Maine (continued) (Box 12)
    Brunswick
    Cousins Island
    H-K
    Kennebunkport
    L-N
    Monhegan Island
    Mt. Desert Island
    Norway
    O
    P-R
    Paris
    Portland
    Rockland
    Stoneham
  - Maine (continued) (Box 13)
    W - Z
  - Maine | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Acadia National Park and Bar Harbor, Mt. Desert Island (2)
    Portland (2)
    State of Maine
  - Maine | Oversize (Box 97 (folder 1))
  - Maine | Miniature (Box 98)
  - Maryland (Box 13)
    Annapolis
    Baltimore
    C-E
    Cumberland
    F-K
    Frederick
    L-R
    Westminster
  - Maryland | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Cambridge
  - Maryland | Oversize (Box 97 (folder 1))
    Ocean City
  - Massachusetts (Box 13)
    A
    Amherst
    B
    Berkshire Hills
  - Massachusetts (continued) (Box 14)
    Boston
    Arboretum
    Commons
    Copley Square
    Faneuil Hall
    General Views
    Copp's Hill Burying Ground
    Harbor
    Harvard University - Law and Medical Schools
    King's Chapel
    Market
    Museum of Fine Arts
    Public Garden
    Public Library
    Railroad Stations
    Paul Revere
    State House
    C
    Harvard University
    Cape Cod
    Concord
  - Massachusetts (continued) (Box 15)
    D
    Deerfield
    Dedham
    Duxbury
    Edgartown
    Fairhaven
    Gloucester
    Great Barrington
    Greenfield
    H-I
    Hadley
    Holyoke
    J-L
    Lenox
  - Massachusetts (continued) (Box 16)
    Marblehead
    Martha's Vineyard
    Mohawk Trail
    Mount Hermon
    N
    Nantucket
    New Bedford
    Newburyport
    Northampton
    Northfield
    O-P
    Pittsfield
    Plymouth
    Provincetown
  - Massachusetts (continued) (Box 17)
    Salem
    Springfield
    Stockbridge
    Sudbury
    T-V
    Williamstown
    Worcester
  - Massachusetts | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Boston (4) Cape Ann, Gloucester, and Rockport
    Lawrence
    Pilgrim Plymouth
    Whipple House, Ipswich
    Worcester (3)
  - Massachusetts | Oversize (Box 97 (folder 1))
    Martha's Vineyard (steamer)
    Pittsfield (5-foot long "Extension Post Card")
  - Michigan (Box 18)
    Detroit
    E-M
    Mackinac Island
    N-S
    Saginaw
  - Minnesota (Box 18)
    Duluth
    Minneapolis
    St. Paul
    Virginia
  - Mississippi (Box 18)
  - Missouri (Box 19)
    A-K
    Kansas City
    L-S
    St. Louis
  - Missouri | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Fort Leonard Wood (2)
  - Montana (Box 19)
    Bozeman
    F-M
    Flathead
    Glacier National Park
    Missoula
    Virginia City
  - Montana | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
  - Montana | Oversize (Box 97 (folder 1))
    West Missoula
  - Nebraska (Box 19)
    A-L
    Lincoln
    Omaha
  - Nevada (Box 20)
  - Nevada | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Las Vegas
  - Nevada | Oversize (Box 97 (folder 1))
  - New Hampshire (Box 20)
    D-E
    Dublin
    Exeter
    F-H
    Hanover
    I-K
    Keene
    L-M
    Lake Sunapee
    Lebanon
    Monadnock Lake and Mountain
    N-O
    Newport
    North Conway
    Peterboro
    Portsmouth
    S-T
  - New Hampshire (continued) (Box 21)
    U-Z
    White Mountains
    Bretton Woods
    Crawford Notch
    Dixville Notch
    Franconia Notch
    Mt. Washington
    Pinkham Notch
  - New Hampshire | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Hampton Beach
    Lake Winnipesauke (2)
    Mt. Washington, White Mountains
  - New Hampshire | Oversize (Box 97 (folder 1))
  - New Jersey (Box 21)
    Asbury Park
    Arcade
    Avenues
    Beach
    Boardwalk
    Buildings, Public
    Casino
    Convention Hall
    Deal Lake
    Esplanade Review
    Fishing Pier
    Ocean Scene
    Parades (includes Baby Parade)
    Restaurant
    Sunset Lake
    Wesley Lake
  - New Jersey (continued) (Box 21-22)
    Atlantic City
    Civic Buildings
    Lighthouse
    Ocean Scenes
    Piers
    B-C
    Camp Dix
    Elizabeth
    F-J
    Jersey City
    K-L
  - New Jersey (continued) (Box 23)
    Lake Hopatcong
    Lakewood
    Montclair
    Morristown
    Banks
    Clubs
    Fire Department
    Fort Nonsense
    Hospitals
    Lakes, Ponds, Rivers
    Library
    Morse Telegraph
    Museums
    Railroad
    Revolutionary War Places
    Schools
    Streets, Avenues, etc.
    Washington's Headquarters
    Newark
  - New Jersey (continued) (Box 24)
    New Brunswick
    Ocean Grove
    Palisades
    Paterson
    Plainfield
    Princeton
    Red Bank
    Somerville
    Trenton
  - New Jersey | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    New Jersey Turnpike (2)
    Old Barracks, Trenton
    Princeton University
    Toms River
  - New Jersey | Oversize (Box 97 (folder 1))
    Fort Lee
  - New Mexico (Box 24)
    Albuquerque
    Santa Fe
  - New Mexico | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    New Mexico (2)
  - North Carolina (Box 72)
    Asheville
    Pinehurst
    Raleigh
    Southern Pines
  - North Carolina | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Great Smoky Mountains National Park (3)
  - North Dakota (Box 72)
    Badlands
  - Ohio (Box 72)
    Cincinnati
    Cleveland
    Business Squares
    Business Streets
    Lakes
    Museum
    Residential District
    Rivers
    Columbus
  - Ohio (continued) (Box 73)
    Dayton
    Lithopolis
    Marion
    Zanesville
  - Ohio | Miniature (Box 98)
  - Oklahoma (Box 73)
    Guthrie
    Oklahoma City
  - Oklahoma | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
    Oklahoma, the Sooner State
  - Oregon (Box 73)
    Columbia River Highway
    Crater Lake
    D-M
    Mt. Hood
    Q-Z
  - Oregon | Souvenir Folders & Sets (Box 96-A)
  - Pennsylvania (Box 73)
    Altoona
    Allentown
    Bethlehem
    Buck Hill Falls
    Carlisle
    Chester
  - Pennsylvania (continued) (Box 74)
    Delaware Water Gap
    Easton
    Erie
    Gettysburg
    Harrisburg
    Hazleton
    Lancaster
    Mauch Chunk
    Montrose
    New Geneva
  - Pennsylvania (continued) (Box 75)
    P
    Pennsburg
    Philadelphia
    Alms House
    Carpenter's Hall
    Centennial 1873
    City Hall
    Fairmount Park
    Founders Week
    Independence Hall
    Liberty Bell
    Libraries
    Sesqui-Centennial 1926
    Streets and Avenues
    Theatres
    U.S. Mint
  - Pennsylvania (continued) (Box 76)
    Pittsburgh
    Poconos
    Reading
    Scranton
    Uniontown
    Valley Forge